<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.1.8">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/teamstupeberron/aurora/main/teamstupeberron/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Cone Of Silence" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_CONE_OF_SILENCE">
        <description>
            <p>When you push the button on this item once a day, it creates a sphere of silence.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Staff Of An Adder" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OF_AN_ADDER">
		<description>
			<p>You can use an action to speak this staff’s command word and throw the staff on the ground within 10 feet of you. The staff becomes a giant constrictor snake under your control and acts on its own initiative count. By using a bonus action to speak the command word again, you return the staff to its normal form in a space formerly occupied by the snake.</p>
			<p class="indent">On your turn, you can mentally command the snake if it is within 60 feet of you and you aren’t incapacitated. You decide what action the snake takes and where it moves during its next turn, or you can issue it a general command, such as to attack your enemies or guard a location.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the snake is reduced to 0 hit points, it dies and reverts to its staff form. The staff then shatters and is destroyed. If the snake reverts to staff form before losing all its hit points, it regains all of them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cleric, druid, warlock</set>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a cleric, druid, or warlock">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
    </element>
	<element name="Sonic Kylie" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_SONIC_KYLIE">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This magical boomerang hits harder on the way back. When you attack with it, roll to hit. If you succeed, The Sonic Kylie does 1d4 bludgeoning damage and automatically returns to your hand. However, if you miss your target, the Sonic Kylie spins off. At the start of your next turn, it returns and you may make a new attack roll with it against the same target. If the new attack roll hits, it instead does 1d4 bludgeoning damage plus 3d6 thunder damage. (effect continues if you miss again). Once the strong hit connects, you may then use your reaction to catch the boomerang. If you do not, it lands 30 feet away in a direction of DM’s choice.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="boomerang">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="range">60/120</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="damage" type="bludgeoning">1d4</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Estus" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_ESTUS">
		<description>
			<p>This bottle has two swigs of healing water, each of which heals 1d12 HP. It refills on a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ball Of Snow Rice" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_SNOWRICEBALL">
		<description>
			<p>This small ball of magical rice restores 4D4+4 HP upon consumption, and another 4D4+4 HP at the start of the next round.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Black and Yellow" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_BLACKNYELLOW">
		<description>
			<p>This black and yellow pendant is made from dragonshard and can cast one of the following spells once a day:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Dust of Dissapearance:</em></strong>  10 ft invisibility for 2d4 minutes</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Flash of Truth:</em></strong>  (Wis Save DC 14), 1 question</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Hold Portal</em></strong></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Great Owl's Shroud" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_GREATOWL_SHROUD">
		<description>
			<p>This draping shoulder cloak flutters softly while worn, even if there isn’t a breeze. The cloak has 10 charges and regains all expended charges daily at dawn. When you take the Attack action while wearing this garment, you can replace one or more of your attacks with a special ranged spell attack using the cloak, expending 1 of its charges for each attack you replace. When you do, you flourish the cloak and release a barrage of magical feathers that fly toward the target. You have a +5 bonus to attack rolls made with the cloak, which have a normal range of 30 feet and a long range of 120 feet. On a hit, the target takes 2d4 + 3 force damage. After the attack, the feathers vanish.</p>
			<p>In addition, you can use a reaction when you fall to cast the “feather fall” spell from the cloak, targeting only yourself. Once this property of the cloak has been used, it can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p>As a Changeling, the cloak changes form when you do, but always into some form of cloak.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Glamoui" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_GLAMOUI">
        <description>
            <p>A small pebble that turns into a minnow in the water and back to a pebble when removed. Belongs to Lyth. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Uggling" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_UGGLING">
        <description>
            <p>A hideous stitched toy bear can activate with the word "Uggling" to say a phrase you give it by being attuned with it. Belongs to Kara. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Etherling" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_ETHERLING">
        <description>
            <p>A whisp of what appears to be cotton but is actually a cloud. By attuning with the command word "Etherling", it hovers around your head and can be moved with concentration. Belongs to Bharush. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Oilifera" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_OILIFERA">
        <description>
            <p>A greyish, dark inky sponge. It magically absorbs wax, oil, and more. Belongs to Ashtari. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Crown of the Woad King" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_WOADCROWN">
        <description>
            <p>A crown to celebrate your glory as a Woad Warrior. Belongs to Yeats. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
	<element name="Iainto Sap" type="Weapon" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_IAINTO_SAP">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CLUBS</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This Sap bypasses damage immunity/reduction, and does non-lethal bludgeoning damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="sp">1</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="bludgeoning">1d4</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CLUB</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cracked Driftglobe" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_CRACKED_DRIFTGLOBE">
		<description>
			<p>This small sphere of thick glass weighs 1 pound. If you are within 60 feet of it, you can speak its command word and cause it to emanate the <em>light</em> spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Liar's Lyre" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_LIARS_LYRE">
		<description>
			<p>This magical instrument's strings reverberate at the sound of a lie you tell, allowing you to weave tall tales and convince others of your lies more easily. You have advantage on any Charisma (Deception) check you make when you spend at least 1 minute attempting to convince a creature of a lie. In addition, when you cast the vicious mockery cantrip and are holding the lyre, the spell save DC is increased by 1. You are proficient with this lyre while you are attuned to the instrument.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Docent (Herzog)" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_DOCENT_HERZOG">
		<description>
			<p>(requires attunement by a warforged)A docent is a small metal sphere, about 2 inches across, studded with dragonshards. To attune to a docent, you must embed the item somewhere on your body, such as your chest or your eye socket.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> A docent is a sentient item of any alignment with an Intelligence of 16, a Wisdom of 14, and a Charisma of 14. It perceives the world through your senses. It communicates telepathically with you and can speak, read, and understand any language it knows </p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Life Support.</em></strong> Whenever you end your turn with 0 hit points, the docent can make a Wisdom (Medicine) check with a +6 bonus. If this check succeeds, the docent stabilizes you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Docent First Aid (Spell).</em></strong> Evocation Cantrip. Verbal, Somatic components. Casting Time: Full Action. The warforged you are inset into can spend a Hit Die to regain 1d4+3 hp. This may only be used while the warforged is nonfunctioning (aka at zero HP).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> The docent knows Common, Draconic, Elven, Giant, Primordial, and Sylvan. It can translate for you and speak aloud to provide translation to those you wish to speak to.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skills.</em></strong> The docent has a +7 to History Checks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spells.</em></strong> The docent can cast Detect Magic at will.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Reach" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_COUATL_HERALDS_REACH">
		<description>
			<p>Weapon (any bow), rare (requires attunement by a creature of good alignment)</p>
			<p class="indent">This wooden bow is carved to resemble a mighty couatl. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The bow has 4 charges and regains 1d3 + 1 expended charges each day at dawn. When you make a ranged attack against a Large or smaller creature with the bow, you can choose a limb to target and expend 1 charge as part of the attack. If the attack hits, the weapon's damage becomes radiant, and the creature is forced to make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, that creature's targeted limb is pinned by radiant tethers of magic: holding it to its body or adjacent surface (if any) for up to 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent">Depending on the pinned limb, the creature may fall over prone, be unable to move, or make weapon attacks with disadvantage while the limb remains pinned in this way. The creature whose limb is pinned by the arrow can use an action to make a DC 15 Strength or Dexterity check (target’s choice). On a success, its limb is no longer pinned by the arrow.</p>
			<p class="indent">Flight of the Couatls. While you're attuned to 3 items with this feature, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, this speed is in addition to your existing flying speed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any crossbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CROSSBOWS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Couatl Herald's Reach {{parent}}</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Hamstrings of Jumping" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_HAMSTRINGS_OF_JUMPING">
		<description>
			<p>Requires attunement by a Warforged. Allows use of the Jump spell as a bonus action at will.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	
	<element name="Breaker Breastplate" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_BREAKER_BREASTPLATE">
		<description>
			<p>If a creature rolls a 1 or 20 while attacking you, they take 4D4 force damage and are knocked prone</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="breastplate">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="armor">Breastplate</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Vain Virtuoso's Violin" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_VAIN_VIRTUOSO_VIOLIN">
		<description>
			<p><em>Requires attunement by a bard)</em></p>
			<p>This finely-crafted instrument is inlaid with intricate pearl designs. When you give another creature a Bardic Inspiration die using this violin, you gain one yourself, which is a d4.</p>
			<p><em>Curse.</em> This violin is cursed, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. When a creature that you can see (including yourself) fails an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw after adding the bonus from your Bardic Inspiration to the total of the roll, you take psychic damage equal to the number rolled on the Bardic Inspiration die as you lose faith in your own abilities. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Bracelet of Rock Magic" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_BRACELET_OF_ROCK_MAGIC">		
		<description>
			<p>While you wear this gold bracelet, it grants you immunity to being petrified, and it allows you to cast <em>flesh to stone</em> (save DC 15) as an action. Once the spell has been cast three times, the bracelet can no longer cast it. Thereafter, you can cast stone shape as an action. After you have done this thirteen times, the bracelet loses its magic and turns from gold to lead. Has 12 charges left.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> The bracelet's affinity with earth manifests as an unusual curse. Creatures of flesh that are strongly related to earth and stone, such as stone giants and dwarves, have advantage on the saving throw against <em>flesh to stone</em> cast from the bracelet. If such a creature's save is successful, the bracelet breaks your attunement to it and casts the spell on you. You make your saving throw with disadvantage, and on a failed save you are petrified instantly. (The Hidden Shrine of Tamoachan)</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">arms</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<!-- condition immunity petrification -->
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Grappling Hook (Arrow)" type="Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_ITEM_GRAPPLING_HOOK_ARROW">
		<description>
			<p>This arrow's head is replaced with a grappling hook and has 50 feet of rope trailing behind it. The hook will pierce through nonmagical, non-adamantine materials in order to stay hooked. The end of the rope is connected to your bow and may be undone as a bonus action. If another grappling hook arrow is fired, and lands within 100 feet of another grappling arrow that is attached to your bow, you may have them be connected. The hooks may be taken out with a successful DC 10 strength check, and may be traversed with a DC 15 Acrobatics check at normal speed, once made the check does not need to be made for another minute. For each time this modification is taken another rope is attached to your bow. If this hits a creature, it connects to the square on the other side of the creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
</elements>