<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="1.1.1">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/teamstupeberron/aurora/main/teamstupeberron/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Cone Of Silence" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_CONE_OF_SILENCE">
        <description>
            <p>When you push the button on this item once a day, it creates a sphere of silence.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Staff Of An Adder" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OF_AN_ADDER">
		<description>
			<p>You can use an action to speak this staff’s command word and throw the staff on the ground within 10 feet of you. The staff becomes a giant constrictor snake under your control and acts on its own initiative count. By using a bonus action to speak the command word again, you return the staff to its normal form in a space formerly occupied by the snake.</p>
			<p class="indent">On your turn, you can mentally command the snake if it is within 60 feet of you and you aren’t incapacitated. You decide what action the snake takes and where it moves during its next turn, or you can issue it a general command, such as to attack your enemies or guard a location.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the snake is reduced to 0 hit points, it dies and reverts to its staff form. The staff then shatters and is destroyed. If the snake reverts to staff form before losing all its hit points, it regains all of them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cleric, druid, warlock</set>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a cleric, druid, or warlock">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
    </element>
	<element name="Sonic Kylie" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_SONIC_KYLIE">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This magical boomerang hits harder on the way back. When you attack with it, roll to hit. If you succeed, The Sonic Kylie does 1d4 bludgeoning damage plus 1d10 poison damage and automatically returns to your hand. However, if you miss your target, the Sonic Kylie spins off. At the start of your next turn, it returns and you may make a new attack roll with it against the same target. If the new attack roll hits, it instead does 1d4 bludgeoning damage plus 1d10 poison damage plus 3d6 thunder damage. (effect continues if you miss again). Once the strong hit connects, you may then use your reaction to catch the boomerang. If you do not, it lands 30 feet away in a direction of DM’s choice.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="boomerang">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="range">60/120</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="damage" type="bludgeoning">1d4</set>
			<set name="damage" type="poison">1d10</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Estus" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_ESTUS">
		<description>
			<p>This bottle has two swigs of healing water, each of which heals 1d12 HP. It refills on a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ball Of Snow Rice" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_SNOWRICEBALL">
		<description>
			<p>This small ball of magical rice restores 4D4+4 HP upon consumption, and another 4D4+4 HP at the start of the next round.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Black and Yellow" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_BLACKNYELLOW">
		<description>
			<p>This black and yellow pendant is made from dragonshard and can cast one of the following spells once a day:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Dust of Dissapearance:</em></strong>  10 ft invisibility for 2d4 minutes</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Flash of Truth:</em></strong>  (Wis Save DC 14), 1 question</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Hold Portal</em></strong></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Great Owl's Shroud" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_GREATOWL_SHROUD">
		<description>
			<p>This draping shoulder cloak flutters softly while worn, even if there isn’t a breeze. The cloak has 10 charges and regains all expended charges daily at dawn. When you take the Attack action while wearing this garment, you can replace one or more of your attacks with a special ranged spell attack using the cloak, expending 1 of its charges for each attack you replace. When you do, you flourish the cloak and release a barrage of magical feathers that fly toward the target. You have a +5 bonus to attack rolls made with the cloak, which have a normal range of 30 feet and a long range of 120 feet. On a hit, the target takes 2d4 + 3 force damage. After the attack, the feathers vanish.</p>
			<p>In addition, you can use a reaction when you fall to cast the “feather fall” spell from the cloak, targeting only yourself. Once this property of the cloak has been used, it can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p>As a Changeling, the cloak changes form when you do, but always into some form of cloak.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Glamoui" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_GLAMOUI">
        <description>
            <p>A small pebble that turns into a minnow in the water and back to a pebble when removed. Belongs to Lyth. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Uggling" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_UGGLING">
        <description>
            <p>A hideous stitched toy bear can activate with the word "Uggling" to say a phrase you give it by being attuned with it. Belongs to Kara. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Etherling" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_ETHERLING">
        <description>
            <p>A whisp of what appears to be cotton but is actually a cloud. By attuning with the command word "Etherling", it hovers around your head and can be moved with concentration. Belongs to Bharush. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Oilifera" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_OILIFERA">
        <description>
            <p>A greyish, dark inky sponge. It magically absorbs wax, oil, and more. Belongs to Ashtari. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
    <element name="Crown of the Woad King" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_WOADCROWN">
        <description>
            <p>A crown to celebrate your glory as a Woad Warrior. Belongs to Yeats. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
	<element name="Iainto Sap" type="Weapon" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_IAINTO_SAP">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CLUBS</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This Sap bypasses damage immunity/reduction, and does non-lethal bludgeoning damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="sp">1</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="bludgeoning">1d4</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CLUB</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cracked Driftglobe" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_CRACKED_DRIFTGLOBE">
		<description>
			<p>This small sphere of thick glass weighs 1 pound. If you are within 60 feet of it, you can speak its command word and cause it to emanate the <em>light</em> spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Liar's Lyre" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_LIARS_LYRE">
		<description>
			<p>This magical instrument's strings reverberate at the sound of a lie you tell, allowing you to weave tall tales and convince others of your lies more easily. You have advantage on any Charisma (Deception) check you make when you spend at least 1 minute attempting to convince a creature of a lie. In addition, when you cast the vicious mockery cantrip and are holding the lyre, the spell save DC is increased by 1. You are proficient with this lyre while you are attuned to the instrument.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Docent (Herzog)" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_DOCENT_HERZOG">
		<description>
			<p>(requires attunement by a warforged)A docent is a small metal sphere, about 2 inches across, studded with dragonshards. To attune to a docent, you must embed the item somewhere on your body, such as your chest or your eye socket.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> A docent is a sentient item of any alignment with an Intelligence of 16, a Wisdom of 14, and a Charisma of 14. It perceives the world through your senses. It communicates telepathically with you and can speak, read, and understand any language it knows </p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Life Support.</em></strong> Whenever you end your turn with 0 hit points, the docent can make a Wisdom (Medicine) check with a +6 bonus. If this check succeeds, the docent stabilizes you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Docent First Aid (Spell).</em></strong> Evocation Cantrip. Verbal, Somatic components. Casting Time: Full Action. The warforged you are inset into can spend a Hit Die to regain 1d4+3 hp. This may only be used while the warforged is nonfunctioning (aka at zero HP).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> The docent knows Common, Draconic, Elven, Giant, Primordial, and Sylvan. It can translate for you and speak aloud to provide translation to those you wish to speak to.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Skills.</em></strong> The docent has a +7 to History Checks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spells.</em></strong> The docent can cast Detect Magic at will.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Reach" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_COUATL_HERALDS_REACH">
		<description>
			<p>Weapon (any bow), rare (requires attunement by a creature of good alignment)</p>
			<p class="indent">This wooden bow is carved to resemble a mighty couatl. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The bow has 4 charges and regains 1d3 + 1 expended charges each day at dawn. When you make a ranged attack against a Large or smaller creature with the bow, you can choose a limb to target and expend 1 charge as part of the attack. If the attack hits, the weapon's damage becomes radiant, and the creature is forced to make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, that creature's targeted limb is pinned by radiant tethers of magic: holding it to its body or adjacent surface (if any) for up to 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent">Depending on the pinned limb, the creature may fall over prone, be unable to move, or make weapon attacks with disadvantage while the limb remains pinned in this way. The creature whose limb is pinned by the arrow can use an action to make a DC 15 Strength or Dexterity check (target’s choice). On a success, its limb is no longer pinned by the arrow.</p>
			<p class="indent">Flight of the Couatls. While you're attuned to 3 items with this feature, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, this speed is in addition to your existing flying speed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any crossbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CROSSBOWS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Couatl Herald's Reach {{parent}}</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Hamstrings of Jumping" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_HAMSTRINGS_OF_JUMPING">
		<description>
			<p>Requires attunement by a Warforged. Allows use of the Jump spell as a bonus action at will.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	
	<element name="Breaker Breastplate" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_BREAKER_BREASTPLATE">
		<description>
			<p>If a creature rolls a 1 or 20 while attacking you, they take 4D4 force damage and are knocked prone</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="breastplate">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="armor">Breastplate</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Vain Virtuoso's Violin" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_VAIN_VIRTUOSO_VIOLIN">
		<description>
			<p><em>Requires attunement by a bard)</em></p>
			<p>This finely-crafted instrument is inlaid with intricate pearl designs. When you give another creature a Bardic Inspiration die using this violin, you gain one yourself, which is a d4.</p>
			<p><em>Curse.</em> This violin is cursed, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. When a creature that you can see (including yourself) fails an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw after adding the bonus from your Bardic Inspiration to the total of the roll, you take psychic damage equal to the number rolled on the Bardic Inspiration die as you lose faith in your own abilities. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Bracelet of Rock Magic" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_BRACELET_OF_ROCK_MAGIC">		
		<description>
			<p>While you wear this gold bracelet, it grants you immunity to being petrified, and it allows you to cast <em>flesh to stone</em> (save DC 15) as an action. Once the spell has been cast three times, the bracelet can no longer cast it. Thereafter, you can cast stone shape as an action. After you have done this thirteen times, the bracelet loses its magic and turns from gold to lead. Has 12 charges left.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> The bracelet's affinity with earth manifests as an unusual curse. Creatures of flesh that are strongly related to earth and stone, such as stone giants and dwarves, have advantage on the saving throw against <em>flesh to stone</em> cast from the bracelet. If such a creature's save is successful, the bracelet breaks your attunement to it and casts the spell on you. You make your saving throw with disadvantage, and on a failed save you are petrified instantly. (The Hidden Shrine of Tamoachan)</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">arms</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<!-- condition immunity petrification -->
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Grappling Hook (Arrow)" type="Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_ITEM_GRAPPLING_HOOK_ARROW">
		<description>
			<p>This arrow's head is replaced with a grappling hook and has 50 feet of rope trailing behind it. The hook will pierce through nonmagical, non-adamantine materials in order to stay hooked. The end of the rope is connected to your bow and may be undone as a bonus action. If another grappling hook arrow is fired, and lands within 100 feet of another grappling arrow that is attached to your bow, you may have them be connected. The hooks may be taken out with a successful DC 10 strength check, and may be traversed with a DC 15 Acrobatics check at normal speed, once made the check does not need to be made for another minute. For each time this modification is taken another rope is attached to your bow. If this hits a creature, it connects to the square on the other side of the creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Healies" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_ITEM_HEALIES">
		<description>
			<p>These boots allow you to do the following things, each once per day:</p>
			<p> 1) As a Reaction, if you are touching the ground and unrestrained, you can hop back five feet [not provoking attacks of opportunity]. If your attacker doesn’t have that range, their attack misses. This also works if you’re right on the edge of a fireball or in line of a lightning bolt or whatever. If moving five feet takes you out of range, you aren’t effected.</p>
			<p> 2) Inside the back half of the right sole is a refillable Stomp Potion. As part of a Movement, you can use it to give yourself a second wind [roll one of your hit dice and regain that many hp].</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">healing, reaction</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Sentira Lens, Light" type="Weapon" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_SENTIRA_LENS_LIGHT">	
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_AMMUNITION, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Sentira Lenses are a hand held ranged weapon that can focus a wielder's psionic potential to fire a harmful bolt of telepathic energy. </p>
			<p>They count as a "psiactive" weapon. a Psiactive ranged weapon draws its power from your innate psionic potential, whether or not you're trained to use it. When attacking with a psiactive weapon, you use your choice of your Intelligence or Charisma modifier for the attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p>You can fire psiactive weapons a number of times equal to twice your proficiency bonus. After that, your psionic potential is temporarily expended and you can't fire another psiactive weapon until you regain your psionic focus by using an action or a bonus action (your choice). Your psionic focus is shared between all psiactive weapons.</p>
			<p>Psiactive weapons aren't considered magical weapons and can't be sensed with the detect magic spell or similar magic. However, they don't function in an antimagic field.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">50</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">twohand</set>
			<set name="range">30/120</set>
			<set name="damage" type="psychic">1d6</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Sentira Lens, Hand" type="Weapon" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_SENTIRA_LENS_HAND">	
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_AMMUNITION, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Sentira Lenses are a hand held ranged weapon that can focus a wielder's psionic potential to fire a harmful bolt of telepathic energy. </p>
			<p>They count as a "psiactive" weapon. a Psiactive ranged weapon draws its power from your innate psionic potential, whether or not you're trained to use it. When attacking with a psiactive weapon, you use your choice of your Intelligence or Charisma modifier for the attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p>You can fire psiactive weapons a number of times equal to twice your proficiency bonus. After that, your psionic potential is temporarily expended and you can't fire another psiactive weapon until you regain your psionic focus by using an action or a bonus action (your choice). Your psionic focus is shared between all psiactive weapons.</p>
			<p>Psiactive weapons aren't considered magical weapons and can't be sensed with the detect magic spell or similar magic. However, they don't function in an antimagic field.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">50</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">3 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="range">30/120</set>
			<set name="damage" type="psychic">1d4</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Sentira Lens, Heavy" type="Weapon" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_SENTIRA_LENS_HEAVY">	
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_AMMUNITION, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_HEAVY, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Sentira Lenses are a hand held ranged weapon that can focus a wielder's psionic potential to fire a harmful bolt of telepathic energy. </p>
			<p>They count as a "psiactive" weapon. a Psiactive ranged weapon draws its power from your innate psionic potential, whether or not you're trained to use it. When attacking with a psiactive weapon, you use your choice of your Intelligence or Charisma modifier for the attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p>You can fire psiactive weapons a number of times equal to twice your proficiency bonus. After that, your psionic potential is temporarily expended and you can't fire another psiactive weapon until you regain your psionic focus by using an action or a bonus action (your choice). Your psionic focus is shared between all psiactive weapons.</p>
			<p>Psiactive weapons aren't considered magical weapons and can't be sensed with the detect magic spell or similar magic. However, they don't function in an antimagic field.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">18 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="range">30/120</set>
			<set name="damage" type="psychic">1d8</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Ashen Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_ASHEN_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>A blade used by knights in service of a kingdom long forgotten to time and whose only remains are ashes and ruins, this weapon takes the appearance of a sharp blade decorated with carvings representing the heads of wolves, when the user lands a precise blow to an enemy the blade leaves a vicious burnt wound on the target.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Magic Weapon.</em></strong> This weapon gains a +2 bonus to any attack and damage roll made using it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Caurerized Wounds.</em></strong> If you make an attack roll with this weapon and you roll a 17 on higher on the d20 you may add 1d6 fire damage to the attack's damage and the target must succeed in a Constitution saving throw (DC = 8 + your Strength/Dexterity Modifier + your proficiency bonus + this weapon's magic bonus) or it will be inflicted by the searing heat of the blade making them unable to recover hit points until the end of their next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ashen Legacy.</em></strong> If you kill a creature using this weapon or use it to strike the corpse of a dead creature, the corpse becomes unable to be used for the usage of any spell or magical effect as the blade's magic leaves a charred and smoking body behind.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">axe, sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe or sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Peniondant" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_PENIONDANT">
		<description>
			<p>An enchanted locket made of solid opal attached to an indestructible chain necklace.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Syranita's Blessing.</em></strong> If the wearer is an aarakocra, you can place a feather that did not come from yourself inside of the locket with Syranita's feather. If the feather is left in the locket for 1 continuous hour, the feather becomes magical. A creature with less than half of their hit points can use an action to touch the magical feather, regaining hit points until they have half of their hit points remaining, rounded up. The feather then disappears. Once this feature is used, it cannot be used again until 7 days have passed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ring of Tressym" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_TRESSYM">
		<description>
			<p>This ring allows the user to polymorph into a Tressym once per day for up to 2 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Living Jar (Small)" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_LIVING_JAR_SMALL">
		<description>
			<p><em>Fillable.</em>Living jars actively seek out people and ask to have things stored inside them, potions, rations, acid, water, dirt. They'll take anything no matter how destructive or corrosive, they'll store it just fine.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Twilight Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_TWILIGHT_BLADE">		
		<description>
			<p>This sword represents the epitome of balance. The weapon has two blades, one forged of golden radiance and the other of obsidian shadow. When drawn, the blades gain a soft aura of light or darkness. If you are proficient with shortswords, longswords, or greatswords, you are proficient with the Twilight Blade.</p>
			<p class="indent">When making an attack with this weapon, you make two attack rolls, one for each blade. On a hit, a blade does 1d4 slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Dawn.</em>When the weapon is held in bright light, the golden blade projects a blade of radiant energy ahead of itself, causing the first attack roll of each attack to be made with advantage and deal radiant damage instead of slashing damage.</p>
			
			<p class="indent"><em>Dusk.</em>When the weapon is held in darkness, a shadowy afterimage of the obsidian blade trails behind it, causing the second attack roll of each attack to be made with advantage and deal necrotic damage instead of slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Antithesis.</em>While the Dawn feature is active, the second attack roll of each attack is made with disadvantage. While the Dusk feature is active, the first attack roll of each attack is made with disadvantage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Twilight.</em>As a bonus action while holding the weapon, you can utter a Command Word (Twilight) that echoes in Abyssal, Celestial, and Infernal. Any creature that hears the Commmand Word and can understand those languages understands the meaning of the word. For the next minute, you gain the benefit of the Dawn and Dusk features, and the Antithesis feature is suppressed. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Light and Shadow.</em>This sword has 3 charges, which you can use to cast spells, and gains 1d2+1 charges with each day at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding the sword, you can spend one or more charges and use an action to speak a Command Word (Daybreak or Nightfall) to cast one of the following spells from the sword without any components except the Command Word spoken.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Daybreak.</em>Daylight. When you cast the Daylight spell using this feature at 5th level or higher, the spell rquires concentration, but the light is sunlight.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Nightfall.</em>Darkness. While you are holding the sword, you treat the magical darkness created by casting the Darkness spell using this feature as nonmagical darkness.</p>
			<p class="indent">For each charge after the first spent while casting, the level of the spell increases by 1. When you cast a spell using this feature, the point chosen can only be on the weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When spoken, these Command Words echo in Abyssal, Celestial, and Infernal. Any creature that hears these Command Words and can understand those languages understands the meaning of the words.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Greataxe of Glory" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_WEAPON_AXE_OF_GLORY">
		<description>
			<p>Draws the eyes of attackers within 15 feet. They must make a will save of dc 16. Upon failure, they must decide to attack the wielder.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">axe, sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe or sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Spear of the Piranha" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_SPEAR_OF_PIRANHA">
		<description>
			<p>If you damaged an enemy with this weapon last turn, this turn attacks do one additional damage to that enemy. This ability stacks.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spear, javelin</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear or javelin">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear||Javelin</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Ring of Spell Storing (Loosened)" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_SPELL_STORING">
		<description>
			<p>This ring stores spells cast into it, holding them until the attuned wearer uses them. The ring can store up to 7 levels worth of spells at a time. When found, it contains 1d6 - 1 levels of stored spells chosen by the GM. It has since been modified with a Loosening Arcane Unguent, incresaing it's capacity from 5 levels to 7.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any creature can cast a spell of 1st through 7th level into the ring by touching the ring as the spell is cast. The spell has no effect, other than to be stored in the ring. If the ring can't hold the spell, the spell is expended without effect. The level of the slot used to cast the spell determines how much space it uses.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing this ring, you can cast any spell stored in it. The spell uses the slot level, spell save DC, spell attack bonus, and spellcasting ability of the original caster, but is otherwise treated as if you cast the spell. The spell cast from the ring is no longer stored in it, freeing up space.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="MournBlade" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_MOURNBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>The blade of this longsword is made of the strongest infernal iron in the Nine Hells, and it is engraved with infernal runes that represent the blessing of Ravanna. Its sharp and dangerous looking gold guard has a deep orange, feline-like blazing eye in the center that seems to be aware of everything in its surroundings and apperas to be constnatly scheming.
			</p>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this sword. If you score a critical hit with it, the target takes 2d8 extra psychic damage and has disadvantage on Wisdom checks and saving throws until the start of its next turn.
			</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> Mourneblade is a sentient lawful evil weapon with an Intelligence of 15, a Wisdom of 16, and a Charisma of 20. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</p>
			<p>The weapon communicates telepathically with its wielder and can speak, read, and understand Common and Infernal.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> The soul of a fierce and narcissistic naityan rakshasa named Prahasta lives within the Mournblade. He was an evil paladin, herald of Ravanna, and chief commander of one of the biggest fiendish armies during the Blood War.</p>
			<p>The weapon abhors demons and any of their creations that led to its fatal demise. It talks in a superior, tyrannical, and strategist tone of voice, but it complements its wielder whenever they deal the killing blow against a creature.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Battle Standard of Laments.</em></strong> You call upon a giant spectral fiery battle standard that saps the enemies' moral in combat by filling their minds with sorrow and grief. Before rolling for initiative, you can use reaction to create a 15-foot radius sphere centered on a point withing 60 feet of you. Creatures within that area must make a DC18 Wisdom saving throw or be influenced by the spectral banner, and subtract 1d6 from the initiative roll. The result can't be reduced lower than a 1.</p>
			<p>Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a non-good aligned creature">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Pendant of the Life Drinker" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_PENDANT_OF_THE_LIFE_DRINKER">
		<description>
			<p>This velvet pendant was crafted by cunning vampires to make mortals succumb to the appeal of the exquisite delight that is blood.</p>
			<p>When attuned to this necklace, you become capable of draining the life of your foes. You can replace one of your melee attacks by a fang attack. Make a melee weapon attack using your strength of Dexterity, on a hit this attack deals 3d8 necrotic damage and you regain a number of hit points equal to the necrotic damage dealt.</p>
			<p>Once per day, whne you should fall to 0 hit points or lower, you can use your reaction to make this attack.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse - Blood Call:</em></strong> After feeding more than 3 times on blood in a day you must succeed on a DC 12 Wisdom saving throw or fall into blood lust for the next 8 hours. Each time you feed on blood after that, the DC increases by 3. When you finish a long rest, it resets.</p>
			<p>While blood lusted you fall under your GM's control and become a bloodthirsty beast with no recognition of friends or foes. Only feeding on blood matters to you. During that period you attract vampires within a 3 mile radius which will try to turn you into one of them. If you survive this curse without becoming a vampire or thrall, the pendant loses all power.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Quiver of Endless Arrows +1" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_QUIVER_OF_ENDLESS_ARROWS">
		<description>
			<p>This enchanted quiver appears to hold 20 arrows or bolts. When one is removed, another one magically appears in its place moments later.</p>
			<p>While attuned to this quiver, ammunition used from it is automatically replaced as it is used. The ammunition produced by the quiver is only considered magical to the attuned, and if taken out of the quiver, it disappears after 1 minute. You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with ranged weapons with these arrows.</p>
			<p>Poisons and oils may still be applied to individual arrows, which retain their potency while in the quiver for the duration.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
    <element name="Etherling(Mourned)" type="Magic Item" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_MAGIC_ITEM_ETHERLING_MOURNED">
        <description>
            <p>What was formerly a whisp of what appears to be cotton but was actually a cloud now cycles between states of being - cloud, hail, water, steam, and back to cloud. By attuning with the command word "Etherling", it hovers around your head and can be moved with concentration. Each utterance of the command word causes it to cycle to the next phase. Belongs to Bharush. Prophetic!</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
    </element> 
	
</elements>