<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.2.3">
			<file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/teamstupeberron/aurora/main/teamstupeberron/spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Silvery Barbs" type="Spell" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_SPELL_SILVERY_BARBS">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
		  <p>You magically distract the triggering creature and turn its momentary uncertainty into encouragement for another creature. The triggering creature must reroll the d20 and use the lower roll.</p>
		  <p class="indent">You can then choose a different creature you can see within range (you can choose yourself). The chosen creature has advantage on the next attack roll, ability check, or saving throw it makes within 1 minute. A creature can be empowered by only one use of this spell at a time.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when a creature you can see within 60 feet of yourself succeeds on an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantenous</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow Of Mnemosyne" type="Spell" source="Team StupEberron" id="ID_TSE_SPELL_SHADOW_OF_MNEMOSYNE">
		<supports>Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Inky deep shadows wreathe your body until the spell ends, causing you to become heavily obscured to others. The shadows turn dim light within 10 feet of you into darkness, and bright light in the same area to dim light.</p>
            <p class="indent">Until the spell ends, you have resistance to psychic damage. In addition, whenever a creature within 10 feet of you hits you with an attack, the uncertainty of what the shadows might contain clutches at that creature, dealing it 2d8 psychic damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">psychic</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a traumatic memory you have collected encased in a gem worth at least 150 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
	</element>
</elements>